



# Muhammad Ibrahim

O Home: House 46, Street 87, G-13/1, 44000, Islamabad, Pakistan

**Email:** <u>ibrahimag99@gmail.com</u> **Phone:** (+92) 3123996083

**Website:** <a href="https://www.muhammadibrahim.com/">https://www.muhammadibrahim.com/</a>

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ibrahimqureshi99

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 08/08/1999 **Nationality:** Pakistani

#### **ABOUT MYSELF**

I am a Frontend Web Developer with more than three years of experience in WordPress, React.js, and Vue.js. I write clean code, enjoy learning new skills, and face challenges with a positive attitude. I have proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. I can solve problems effectively and work well with others.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## [15/01/2024 - Current] Frontend Developer - Team Lead

**AGInfoTech** https://aginfotech.co/

City: Lahore | Country: Pakistan | Name of unit/department: Software Development

- Promoted to Frontend Lead in July 2024, successfully managing and mentoring a team of frontend developers.
- Spearheaded the development of complex web applications, including high-profile websites for a global architectural firm, Al-driven sales tools, and advanced accounting software.
- Ensured seamless integration between frontend and backend through continuous collaboration with backend developers.
- Optimized server-side and client-side rendering, enhancing development efficiency and post-production performance.
- · Streamlined deployment processes by leveraging Docker and AWS, leading to faster and more reliable rollouts.

## [ 01/11/2022 - 15/02/2024 ] Frontend Web Developer

**AlphaSquad** https://www.alphasquad.tech/

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan | Name of unit/department: Development

- Developed 5+ complex web applications and web portals using React, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS.
- Converted Figma designs to pixel perfect UI, collaborating on product and web design, ensuring seamless user experiences.
- Utilized cloud services for efficient application deployment.
- RESTful APIs implementation and stores creation and management for data handling

[ 01/02/2022 - 31/10/2022 ] **Freelance Developer** 

#### Freelance

**City:** Remote | **Country:** Pakistan

- Revamped and improved the UI/UX of 20+ projects, resulting in an average increase of 30% in user engagement.
- Collaborated with international clients on diverse projects, leading to a 20% increase in client satisfaction.

- Successfully integrated SEO techniques into various projects, ensuring an average page load time of under 2 seconds.
- Delivered projects on schedule and within budget, achieving 95% on-time completion rate with 98% client retention rate.

## [ 01/08/2016 – 31/07/2020 ] **Junior Web developer**

Fleekbiz Pvt Ltd https://fleekbiz.com/

City: Islambad | Country: Pakistan

- Developed responsive HTML/CSS/IS projects, prioritizing user-friendly design and exceptional user experiences.
- Successfully delivered 4–5-page websites featuring core functionality and interactive contact forms.
- Utilized jQuery along with various CSS pre-processors such as SASS and SCSS to enhance website functionality and aesthetics.

## [ 01/07/2020 - 17/01/2022 ] **Web Development Executive**

Digital Marvels Pvt Ltd https://digimarv.com

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

- Revamped and improved the UI/UX of 20+ projects, resulting in an average increase of 30% in user engagement.
- Collaborated with international clients on diverse projects, leading to a 20% increase in client satisfaction.
- Successfully integrated SEO techniques into various projects, ensuring an average page load time of under 2 seconds.
- Delivered projects on schedule and within budget, achieving 95% on-time completion rate with 98% client retention rate.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAIN-**ING

## [01/08/2023 - Current] **The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp**

Udemy https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-web-development-bootcamp/

https://www.udemy.com/course/the-complete-web-developmentbootcamp/

[ 01/08/2023 – Current ]

**Udemy** https://www.udemy.com/course/100-days-of-code/

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## **Digital Skills - Test Results**

	Information and data literacy	ADVANCED	Level 5 / 6
20 20	Communication and collaboration	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6

0	Digital content creation	ADVANCED	Level 6 / 6
---	--------------------------	----------	-------------



Problem solving

**ADVANCED** Level 6 / 6

Results from a self-assessment based on The Digital Competence Framework 2.1

## **My Digital Skills**

## **MS Office**

Microsoft Office | Microsoft Word | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Powerpoint

#### **Personal Skills**

Organizational and planning skills | Good listener and communicator | Team-work oriented | Critical thinking

### **Frontend Development**

Web (HTML,CSS, JS, XML) | PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery | Competent with some programming languages like: Java, C++, Html, CSS, Javascript. | Javascript: jQuery, React, Redux, nodejs | React / React Hooks/ React Routers/ Redux: Basics | React, Next.js, React Native | Vue.js (2 &3) | Vue/Nuxt.js | WEB DESIGN: HTML, SCSS, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, BOOTSTRAP, MATERIAL UI | Bootstrap and Tailwind CSS | Good Knowledge in Content Management System using WORDPRESS | REST API management | Basic Knowledge of SEO

## **Backend Development**

NodeJS and ExpressJS Basics

#### **Version Control**

GIT version control, Linux Command | git, github, WireShark, Docker, Azure, AWS

#### **Other Skills**

Operating System:Windows | Advanced skiils on using the internet as a work and troubleshooting tool | SoftwareHardware Installation Troubleshooting and Maintenance | Linux(create, copy and delete files from terminal) | Operating System:Linux | Knowl edge in Windows, MacOS and Linux | Figma & Adobe XD